<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Physics Programming on Lx&#39;Log</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/physics-programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Physics Programming on Lx&#39;Log</description>
    <image>
      <title>Lx&#39;Log</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.138.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/physics-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Can Python Improve Work Flow in Data Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-10-12-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-10-12-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog serves as a memorial for the project titled &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/2_project/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;A versatile Python tool box for data analysis&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;
to keep notes of why i started and what i learned from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in a laboratory, I spend a good amount of time on analyzing data acquired from various apparatus in the course of my daily routine. To drive the circle of workflow comprising experimental design, implementation and analysis efficiently, it is beneficial and advisable to get as much as information from data in limited time. It would be awful if one missed fantastic experimental ideas due to a lack of knowledge and understanding in existing data. In general, this requires practical thoughts and technique improvements in preparing data (pre-processing) and visualizing data (plotting).  On one hand, I developed this tool box for my personal use and take it as an experimental attempt to improve the workflow for a laboratory researcher in a data-rich disciplinary, like physics and biology. On the other hand, I hope it, as an open-source project, can also encourage and inspire interested researchers to integrate a bit Python into their workflow for personalized purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
